So, I'd like to talk to you about some research that I find particularly interesting.
我将介绍一些我认为非常有趣的研究项目
And I think it's a great example to illustrate
这些项目可以很好地解释
the reward hypothesis that was introduced in the previous video.
我在上个视频中介绍的奖励假设
Google DeepMind recently addressed the problem of teaching a robot to walk.
Google DeepMind 最近解决了如何指导机器人行走这个问题
Among other problem domains,
除了其他问题领域之外
they worked with a physical simulation of a humanoid robot and they
他们利用一个类人机器人模拟
managed to apply some nice reinforcement learning to get great results.
并通过运用一些强大的强化学习技术获得了很棒的结果
As you learned in an earlier video,
正如你在上个视频中所了解的
in order to frame this as a reinforcement learning problem,
为了将此问题构建成强化学习问题
we'll have to specify the state's actions and rewards.
我们需要指定状态 动作和奖励
We'll dedicate two videos to this example and we'll begin by detailing the actions.
我们会将此示例分成两个视频 并详细介绍动作
These are the decisions that need to be made in order for the robot to walk.
动作是为了使机器人能行走必须做出的决策
Now, the humanoid has several joints,
该类人机器人具有多个接合点
and the actions are just the forces that
动作是机器人运用到关节
the robot applies to its joints in order to move.
以便移动的力
Because the robot has an intelligent method
因为机器人能够通过智能方法
for deciding these forces at every point in time,
判断在每个时间点运用什么样的力
that will be sufficient to get it walking.
从而使其能够行走
And what about the states?
状态呢？
The states are the context provided to the agent for choosing intelligent actions.
状态是提供给智能体的环境信息 使其能够选择合理的动作
In this context, the state at any point in time
在此示例中 任何时间点的状态
contain the current positions and velocities of all of the joints,
包含所有接合点的当前位置和速度
along with some measurements about the surface that the robot was standing on.
以及关于机器人所站地面的测量结果
These measurements captured how flat or inclined the ground was,
这些测量结果表示地面的平坦程度或坡度
if there was a large step along the path and so on.
以及道路上是否有一个大的台阶 等等
The researchers at Google DeepMind also added contact sensor data,
Google DeepMind 研究人员还添加了接触传感器数据
so that it could determine if the robot was still walking or if it had fallen over.
从而判断机器人是否依然在行走 或者绊倒了
The idea is that based on the information in the state,
原理是智能体必须根据状态中的信息
the agent has to plan its next action.
规划下一步的动作
After all, if there's a step along the path,
毕竟 如果道路上有台阶
that will require a different type of movement than if the ground were completely flat.
则与完全平坦的地面相比 将需要完全不同的动作
We'll design the reward as a feedback mechanism that
我们将奖励设计为一种反馈机制
tells the agent that it has chosen the appropriate movements.
告诉智能体它选择了正确的动作
The reward will be our way of telling the agent, "Good job,
奖励是告诉智能体以下反馈的一种形式
for not running into that wall or too bad,
“很棒 没有撞到墙上
you missed that step and fell down."
或者糟糕 没有看到台阶并摔倒了”
That's just the main idea and we'll go into depth in the next video.
这只是总体概念 我们将在下个视频中深入了解